Serhii Bilous

Senior Front-End Engineer

Professional Summary

Passionate Senior Software Engineer with over 9 years of experience specializing in Front-End development.

Visa Status

I just moved to the US by the <u>United for Ukraine</u> program.

Address

West New York, NJ willing to relocate inside the US

Contact

serhiybilouss@gmail.com 201-253-3046 linkedin.com/in/serhii-bilous/ serhiibilous.com

Technical skills

- Javascript, Typescript
- React Js, Next js, React Native, Vue Js, CSS/SCSS, CSS-in-JS, HTML5
- Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS
- Jest, react-testing-library, Cypress
- OOP, SOLID, DRY, Functional programming
- Rest API, GraphQL, Web Sockets
- Agile/Scrum

Working Experience

Senior Front-End Engineer

Grainger Remote - Full-time / Contract Jun 2022 - Dec 2022

- I updated the product recommendation system on the front end of the app and created a single recommendation flow system, which resulted in a 250% increase in revenue for this feature.
- Added search personalization for registered users, which increased the average check by 1.2 times average.
- As a senior developer, I conducted over 5 training sessions on React js.
- Contributed to the company-wide code review guide and code style.

Senior Software Engineer

AXDRAFT (an Onit company)

Dec 2021 - May 2022

On-site Ukraine / Full-time

 Built a new version of our own online editor for documents with such features: commenting, editing with approving or rejecting changes, history, and converting DOC files to an online version, and saving them again as a DOC file.

This was done briefly and under challenging circumstances, 6 months, and during the war in the country.

• I did one redesign for an essential site section, which gave great user reviews.

Senior Software Engineer

Deem, Inc.

Jun 2019 - Nov 2021

Remote - Full-time / Contract

- Starting from the beginning, I was an architect for a single-page application from scratch (rebuilt from an old SSR) based on React js, GraphQL, and Node js.
- Was a primary contributor to the code style, code review process, and application documentation. As a result, the new developer starts work productively in 2 weeks.
- Closely collaborated with a design team and, using a storybook, created a super helpful UI kit with components used in the app, which increased the creation of new features in few times.
- Based on created and constantly updated architecture. Created a PWA using already-built components, which saves the company a lot of money. (Not to hire a separate Android dev team).
- Managed small teams during feature releases. Investigating tasks, code review, managed task flow, and was responsible for each iteration step.

Software Engineer

Taxes for Expats (TFX)

Remote - Full-time / Contract

• Mainly focused as a UI developer, I did 3 redesigns of the app. With excellent performance on static sites, over 95 ratings on google page speed for all pages (mobile and desktop).

- Created a Mailing template system with more than 300 emails for different purposes (test on all popular mail clients)
- Contributed to a brand new app created from scratch as a primary Front-End developer by working on the architecture and code style.

Software Engineer

RIA.com

Jan 2015 - Oct 2016

Oct 2016 - May 2019

On-site Ukraine

- I started work as part of the first Agile team in the company. It was a great success in increasing productivity and then sharing this experience with all teams in the company.
- Built a custom specialized JS framework using pure Javascript with
- the Component approach.
- I redesigned the existing functionality of the project with new, faster, and better technologies. Increase compiling speed 2 times and page speed 1.5 times.

Front-End Engineer

Upwork (freelance)

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

Remote

- Owned such achievements as Raising talent and top-rated freelancer on Upwork. 30+ Total jobs and 500 total hours.
- Created over 50 websites with an average review is 4.9 stars.
- I worked closely with clients as an advisor/architect developer to provide the best solution to their needs and requirements.
- Worked with CMS such as WordPress and Drupal. And UI libraries such as Bootstrap and Material UI to create scalable and customizable websites.

Education

Master's degree - Research Engineer Ukraine/Vinnytsia Bachelor's degree - Design Engineer Ukraine/Vinnytsia

2012 - 2014

2008 - 2012

Projects

BDiary - An application for work in the Beauty industry

April 2021 - Sep 2021

Worked as a second Engineer to lunch a new version of the application.

Sirko - Reviews and ratings of companies for importing cars

Sep 2021 - May 2022 from the USA and Europe.

The founder. Successfully launched the service despite all circumstances in the Country.